Vaasudevan Srinivasan

637, Graham Avenue Fredericton, N.B., E3B 4C2 (506) 471-3194 | vaasu.devan@unb.ca vaasudevans.github.io

Profile Summary

Geodesy and Geomatics Graduate student in University of New Brunswick. Relevant work experience includes development using open source GIS tools and python packages, GIS analysis and building Geodatabases. Self-driven, both process and result oriented with good communication and analytical skills. Optimistic attitude, motivated, development skills and interests to learn new skills will make me an effective addition to any team.

Education

Master of Engineering in Geodesy and Geomatics, University of New Brunswick, Fredericton Sep 2018 - present

• 4.2 / 4.3 GPA with expected graduation in Dec 2019

Bachelor of Engineering in GeoInformatics, Anna University, Chennai, India

2014 - 2018

• Graduated in May 2018 with 8.07 GPA (on a 10 scale)

Employment Experience

Summer Student (GIS) in Transmission & System Operator Division – NB Power

May 2019 – Aug 2019

• Co-operative Work Education term during the summer dealing New Brunswick's Road Network

Digital Technician for Prof. Maria Papaioannou, Classics and Ancient History, UNB

Sep 2018 - Mar 2019

- Created 3D models of the Ancient Abdera site, Greece using the existing site layout and Terrestrial Laser Scanning data and LAS datasets
- Independently developed a website with the information about the project and also the reconstructed models exported from Sweet Home 3D. Link: abdera-thrace.github.io

Student Intern – UNB Sodexo services

Sep 2018 – present

- Coordinating with a team for Catering events and showing strong communication and trained to work in a fast-paced environment; adhere to all food and health regulations and process financial transactions
- Demonstrating responsible, punctual and work-ethics during the whole time

GIS Developer – kCube Consultancy Services, Chennai, India

Jul 2017 - Jan 2018

- Analyzed and developed risk raster models using GRASS GIS and python with the accidents data for the client
- Showed communication and organizational skills in weekly meetings and daily reports to the project manager
- Showcased the application skills by implementing the concepts in both spatial and programming domain

Indian Academy of Science Summer Research Fellow – Tezpur University, Assam

May, June 2017

- Developed a user-friendly software for batch processing and codaQback computation of Seismic waves using python (tkinter, matplotlib and scipy)
- Implemented the same software as a web app using python (django, bokeh and scipy) Dec 2018

Coursework / Project work

GIS and Image Processing

Fredericton: KnowYourRoute using ESRI JS API 3.28 (Link)

April 2019

• Display risk level and statistics for generated routes for selected points on map

Support Vector Machine implementation for Satellite Imagery

April 2019

Site Assessment for Renewable Energy in New Brunswick using ArcGIS, Leaflet

Nov 2019

• Made an assessment on possible sites for solar, geothermal and tidal power stations in NB

WebGIS Portal for Ponneri Taluk (India) using Django, Leaflet

April 2018

• Created a web portal with the surveyed thematic information and integrated them with GIS

Natural Language Processing (using Python builtin modules)

Sep to Dec 2018

- Information retrieval based Chatbot
- Sentiment Analysis, Language Models, POS Tagger

Python modules • cowsay • periodic elements • flames • thirukkural

Web applications are linked at <u>vaasus.pythonanywhere.com</u> | Github link: <u>https://github.com/VaasuDevanS</u>

Relevant Skills

GIS – GRASS GIS, ArcGIS, PostGIS, Leaflet, ESRI JS API

Programming Languages – Python, C, C++, Javascript, SQL, R, Bash

Python Frameworks – <u>DataScience</u>: Numpy, Pandas, Scipy, Matplotlib | <u>Machine-Learning</u>: Scikit-learn, Tensorflow <u>Web</u>: Django, Requests | <u>GUI</u>: Tkinter | <u>GIS</u>: Arcpy, GRASS

Operating systems – Ubuntu-Linux (can also live with only terminal), Windows

Development Environments – Vim, Jupyter-notebook, Atom

Version Control – git

Softwares - Microsoft package, Libreoffice, GIMP

Volunteering / Managerial Roles

• Senior Executive Member in	Students Quality	Council' in Anna	University

2016 to 2018

• Fund Raiser for 'Siruthuligal Charity Club' in Anna University

2017 to 2018

• Event Organizer during Inter-college synposium

2018

Personal Interests and Hobbies

• Chess fanatic (chess.com Rating: 1233) • Avid reader of Kalki • Solving different Rubik's cubes